We've become bored With watching actors give us phony emotions.
We're tired Of pyrotechnics and special effects.
While the world He inhabits...
Is, in some respects, Counterfeit,
There's nothing fake About truman himself--
No scripts No cue cards.
It isn't always shakespeare, But it's genuine.
It's a life.
I'm not going to make it.
(现场直播)
You're going to have To go on without me.
(毕楚门饰演毕楚门)
No way, mister.
You're going to the top Of this mountain,
Broken legs and all.
(基斯督创作)
We find many viewers Leave him on all night for comfort.
You're crazy, You know that?
(乔韩娜饰演美露)
Well, for me, There is no difference between a private life And a public life.
My life...is my life, is the truman show.
The truman show Is...   A lifestyle.
It's a noble life.
It is...a truly blessed life.
Yeah, tell me something I  don't   know.
All right. Promise me One thing, though.
If i die before i reach The summit,
You'll use me as An alternative source of food.
Ew. Gross.
(高路易饰演马龙)
It's all true. It's all real.
Nothing here is fake.Nothing you see On this show is fake.
It's merely controlled.
楚门的世界
Eat me, damn it.That's an order.
Maybe just Your love handles.
I have love handles?
Yeah.Little ones.
Meryl: truman! You're going To be late.
Ok!
[sighs]
[birds twitter]
Good morning.
Morning. Morning.
Oh, and in case I don't see you,
Good afternoon, Good evening, And good night.
[all laugh]
Morning. Morning, spencer.
[barks] Hey, pluto.No, no, no. Get down.
Spencer: He won't hurt you.
Get down. Ha ha. I know.It's just me.
Come on, pluto.
[barks]
Ohh!
Holy cow.
What is it?
Radio: here's A news flash just in.
An aircraft in trouble Began shedding parts
As it flew over seahaven Just a few moments ago.
Wow. Luckily, No one was hurt. But, hey, How do you feel today?
You thinking of Flying somewhere?
Nope. No? Good.
This is classical clive With classical drive, So why don't you forget About the perils of flying,
Settle back, and let This music calm you down?
[classical Piano music plays]
Dog fancy,  please.
Thank you very much.
Truman: ahh! Give me a paper there, Will you, earl?
Oh, and, uh... One of these For the wife. Loves Her fashion mags.
Will that be all For you, truman? That's the whole Kit and caboodle.
Catch you later. Ok.
Yep.
Man: good morning. Hey. Hank.
Morning, truman.
Both: Good morning, truman.
Hey, how are you, guys? Beautiful day, Isn't it? Oh. Always.
Oh, and how's Your lovely wife? Good, good. How about yours?
Oh, couldn't be better.
Um, nice talking To you, truman.
Fine, fine, fine.
You, too. We must go now.
Hey, think about That policy, huh?
Ok, that's 2 for 1. That's a good deal. Doppelganger special.
Twins: right.
Hey. Hi.
Hey, fellas. You going in?
Go ahead. Hey. Go ahead. No, you first, Please.
谢谢
I'm not that anxious To get there.
Ohh...
[workers chatter, Telephones ring]
[softly] Yes, hello. Could i have directory Assistance for fiji, please?
Fiji islands.
Truman, Did you see this?
Ha! Uh, i'm sorry, ma'am. If--if he's in a coma, He's probably uninsurable.
[softly] Hello? Yes. Uh, fiji, please.
Do you have a listing For lauren garland?
Nothing listed?
Ok. Do you have A sylvia garland?
"s" for sylvia.
Nothing?
Ok. Thank you.
[coughs]
Lawrence. Hey, burbank.
Got a prospect In wells park
I need you to close.
W-wells park?
On, uh...Harbor island?
You know another one?
Well, i can't do it.
I, uh, have An appointment. Dentist. Or... Yeah.
You're going to lose A lot more than your teeth If you don't meet Your quota.
Look, truman...They're making cutbacks At the end of this month.
Cutbacks?
Yeah. Now, you need this.
Besides, a half hour Across the bay, A little sea air...Would do you good.
Hey, thanks.
[snaps fingers]
(港岛渡轮码头)
Hello. Ferry still here, huh?
Thought i might have Missed it.
One-way or return?
Return.
There you go, sir.
Heh heh.
[shutters open Electronically]
[sighs]
[shudders]
Uhh...
Do you need Any help, sir?
You go ahead. I'll--i'll be fine.
Heh. Yeah.
Hi, honey.
Look what i got free At the checkout.
It's a chef's pal.
It's a dicer, grater, Peeler--all in one.
Never needs sharpening, Dishwasher safe.
Wow. That's amazing.
Meryl: truman...
You missed a spot.
Oh, jesus.
[lawn mower]
Mmm.
That  is a beer.
You know, i'm thinking About getting out, marlon.
Yeah? Out of what?
Out of my job, Out of seahaven.
Off this island. Out.Out of your job? What the hell's wrong With your job?
You have a great job, Truman. You have a desk job.
I'd kill for a desk job.
Here you go.
You should try stocking Vending machines for a living.
No, thanks. Now, there's excitement.
[both laugh]Don't you ever Get antsy? Itchy feet?
Where's there to go?
Fiji.
[laughs]
Where the hell's fiji? Near florida?
Hmm.
See here?
Yeah. This is us...
And all the way Around here...
Fiji.
You can't get Any further away Before you start Coming back.
You know, there are Still islands in fiji where no human being Has ever set foot.
Whoo.
So, when are you Going to go?
It's not that simple.
It takes...Money, Planning.
I can't just up and go.
Right.
I'm going to do it. Don't worry about that.
Bonus time is just Around the corner.
Hmm.
Hey, you coming For a drink?
No. I can't tonight.
I don't like the look Of that weather, son. I think we should Head back.
Oh, no, dad. Not yet. No, come on. We should go back.
A bit farther. Listen-- Please?
Ok.
Yes.
[thunder]
Daddy!
Ohh!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Oh
[thunder]
You're soaked. Where have you been?
I figure if we can Scrape together 8,000--
Every time you and marlon Get together-- We can bum around the world For a year on that.
And then what, truman? We'd be where we were 5 years ago.
You're talking Like a teenager.
Well, maybe i feel Like a teenager.
We have mortgage payments, Truman.
We have car payments. What, we're just going To walk away from our financial Obligations?
It would be An adventure.
I thought we were going To try for a baby.
Isn't that enough Of an adventure?
That can wait.
I want to get away--See some of the world
Honey, you want to be An explorer?
Explore.
This'll pass.
We all think like this Now and then.
Let's get you out of These wet clothes, hmm?
Come to bed.
You never See anything anyway.
They always...Turn the camera And play music and...
You know, The wind blows in, And the curtains move, And you don't See anything.
Dog fancy,  please.
Dog fancy.
Thank you.
[dog barks]
Paper, earl, please. Paper.
Oh...I might as well Pick one of these up.
For the wife? She's got to have them.
Anything else, truman? That's the whole Ball of wax.
Catch you later.
Ok.
Dad?
Ohh! Hey, what are you Doing?
Hey! What the--
Get out of the way!
Stop them!
Ohh!
Stop those people!
Stop! Stop!
Hey! Open the doors! Somebody Stop the bus!
Stop the bus!
Somebody stop it!
Somebody stop the bus!
Stop the bus!
Aah!
It doesn't sound insane At all, truman.
I see him 10 times a week In a hundred Different faces.
I almost hugged A perfect stranger In the salon Last thursday.
It was dad.
I swear. Dressed like A homeless man.
And you know what else Was strange?
A businessman and a woman With a little dog came out of nowhere and forced him Onto a bus.
Well, it's about time they cleaned up The trash downtown
Before we become just like The rest of the country.
They never found Dad's body.
Maybe somehow-- Oh, god.
I'm telling you, If it wasn't him, It was his twin.
Did dad have A brother?
Truman, you know Perfectly well. That your father Was an only child
Just like you.
Now, sweetie...You're just feeling bad Because of what happened--
You sailing off Into that storm.
But i've never Blamed you, truman...
And i don't blame you now.
[door opens]
Meryl: truman?
[objects clatter]
What are you doing Down here?
Fixing the mower.
[objects clatter]
[blows]
Saw my father Today.
I know.
Your mother called.
You really shouldn't Upset her like that.
Did you want-- What did you want?
I made macaroni.
I'm not hungry.
You know...You really ought To throw out that mower.
Get one of those new Elk rotaries.
[meryl leaves]
[footsteps upstairs]
What's he doing?
See, they Got rid of her, But they couldn't erase The memory.
The memory of who?
Shh.
Man: hey, hey. Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
[trumpet playing]
[continues playing]
[mutes]
[marlon playing trumpet]
Oh! Ow!
Whoa. Ow!
Excuse me. Hi. Hi.
I'm so sorry I fell on you like that. It's ok.
I'm just--i've been Such a klutz all day. It's all right.
Sprained this ankle. Oh, my goodness.
Oh, i'm so sorry. I'm so sorry to fall on you Like that.
Oh, that's all right. Don't worry about it.
I'm meryl. Hi. I'm truman.
Hey. Nice to meet you.
Man: whoo!
Friends say it's fine
Friends say It's good
Everybody says it's Just like rock and roll
Move like a cat
Talk like a rat
Sting like a bee
Babe, I wanna be your man
And it's plain to see
You were meant for me
Yeah, i'm your boy
Twentieth century toy
Friends say it's fine
Friends say It's good
Everybody says
It's just like Rock and roll
Fly like a plane
Drive like a car
All i can handle
Babe, I wanna be your man
Well, it's plain to see
You were meant for me
Yeah, i'm your toy
Twentieth century boy
Twentieth century toy
I wanna be your boy
Truman, you've Studied enough.
No. I got to commit this To memory.
Come on, truman, One ice-cold brewski.
Come on.
Come on. You're going to have To copy off me, So be careful.
I know it.
No? You're a better person Than i am.
See you later.
Ok. Bye.
Bye. See you later, loser.
Ow! Shh!
[sighs]
Hi.
Konnichi-wa.
What?
Oh. You take japanese.
Oh, yes. Yeah.
Lauren, right?
It's on the...
Lauren. Right, right.
I'm truman burbank.
Yeah...I--i know.
[whispering] you know, i'm not Allowed to talk to you.
Really?
Yeah. Well, I can understand that. I'm a pretty dangerous Character.
I'm sorry. It's not up to me.
A girl's Got to be careful.
You have a boyfriend, Right?
No, it's not that.
Was it meryl, that girl That was with me?
We're not--we don't--We're not--we're just-- We're friends.
It's nothing like that.
It's how i look? Not your type?
No.
I like your pin.
(怎样收场?)
I was wondering that Myself.
Mmm. Would you want to...Maybe possibly...
Sometime go out for Some pizza or something?
Like, friday?
Saturday? I can't.
Sunday, monday, Tuesday?
(现在)
We have finals tomorrow.
Yeah, i know.
If we don't go now, It won't happen.
Do you understand?
So, what do you want to do?
[door opens]
[laughing]
Whoo-hoo!
Please keep your hands Inside the car!
This is my favorite Pizza place.
Tony! One large, Extra plankton.
We have so little time. They're going to be here Any minute.
Who are? They don't want me Talking to you.
Then don't talk.
[car approaching]
They're here.
Truman. What do they want?
Listen to me. Everybody knows about you. Everybody knows Everything you do.
They're pretending, truman. Do you understand? Everybody's pretending.
Lauren, I don't know--No, my name's not lauren.
It's sylvia. My name's sylvia.
Sylvia? Yeah.
Lauren, sweetheart, Not again.
Hey, wait a minute. Who are you?
I'm her father! What?
I've never even Seen him before.
Honey, please.
He's lying. Truman, please, Don't listen to him. Everything i've told you Is the truth.
This, it's fake. It's all for you.
I don't understand. The sky and the sea, Everything--it's a set.
It's a show. Everybody's watching you. Please don't listen to him.
He's gonna lie to you. They're watching us now.
What's going on? Schizophrenia. She has episodes.
Please. Oh, no! Father: we've tried Everything.
[honking horn]
Hypnotism, Shock therapy.
Don't worry. You're not the first.
Sylvia: truman! She brings all her Boyfriends down here.
Sylvia: what's he saying? Truman, he's lying!
Get out of here. Come and find me.
Don't worry.
We're going To fiji.
Fiji. We're Moving to fiji.
Fiji?
Sylvia!
Hey!
Why didn't he just Follow her to fiji?
His mother got sick, Really sick.
He couldn't leave her. He's kind. Maybe he's too kind.
I can't believe he married Meryl on the rebound.
Excuse me.
Come on, sal. We've already got this On the greatest hits tape.
Can i borrow that?
(怎样收场?)
Close, but no cigar.
[sighs]
Radio announcer: And it's another beautiful day In paradise, folks
But don't forget to buckle up Out there in radio land.
[malfunctions] remem-- Good driver--good--good--good.
Good--good--good-- Good--good.
Driver--good--driver--good.
Good--good--good.
[static]
Man: wait for the cue. Wait for the cue.
Man: stand by, one.
[static]
Man: countdown to action.
Stand by, one.
He's heading west On stewart.
Stand by, all extras. He'll be on you In about 90 seconds.
Props, make sure The coffee's hot.
Ok, he's making his turn Onto lancaster square.
(兰嘉士打广场)
Aah! Man on radio: oh, my god. He nearly hit her. Something's wrong. Change frequencies.
[loud feedback]
Radio announcer: ouch. Sorry about that, folks.
I guess we picked up a police Frequency or something. It sometimes happens, And it can drive you crazy.
Ok, it's classical clive Back in here,
And we've still got Some great music up ahead,
But hey, Don't forget to buckle up.
Remember safety. A good driver is a safe driver.
A safe driver is what? Yes.
[turns radio off]
Morning, ma'am.
[electrical buzzing]
I love that idea.
It's pretty cool, Isn't it?
Yeah, i love it.
[speaking spanish]
[ding]Can i help?
Yeah. I have An appointment at gable Enterprises.
That's impossible.
What's happening? Guard: nothing.
Just tell me What's happening.
Got to go, sir. We're remodeling.
No, you're not. What are those people Doing back there?
It's none of Your business.
If you don't tell me what's Happening, i'll report you!
You're trespassing.
Right.
Marlon!
Truman. What are you Doing here?
[whispering] I gotta talk to you.
It's a bad time, ok? I'm way behind.
I'm onto something, marlon. Something big.
You ok? You look like shit.
I think i'm mixed up In something. Mixed up in what?
There's no point Trying to explain it, But a lot of strange things Have been happening.
[stammering]
The people on the elevator. There was No backing on it.
I looked out. There was people there.
And on the radio On the way to work,
It starts Following me along, Talking about everything That i'm doing.
You know what i mean? Truman, look, this is One of your fantasies.
I think This is about my dad. Your dad?
I think he's alive.
Yeah. I'll tell you About it later. I'm definitely Being followed.
Who?
It's hard to tell. They look just like Regular people.
How about those two?
Truman: i don't know. Could be.
It's when i'm unpredictable, That's--they can't...
Did anything happen? No.
Mm-hmm. We gotta Get out of here.
You ready to go?
No. I just Came here. Come on.
I told you i can't.
[growls]
You're gonna get both our asses Fired. You know that.
Ok, man, Let's do it.
What? Whatever you say.
I'm game.
Marlon: what are you Talking about? Yes, siree. Your birthday Comes but once a year.
Truman: maybe i'm being Set up for something.
You ever think About that, marlon?
Like your whole life has been building Towards something?
Mmm, no.
When you were Hauling chickens In the summer For kaiser
What was The furthest You ever got Off the island?
Went all over. Never found a place Like this, though.
Look at that sunset, Truman.
It's perfect.
Yeah. That's the big guy.
Quite a paintbrush He's got.
Yup.
Just between you And me, marlon...
I'm going away For a while.
Really?
Yeah.
Mother: oh, little angel.
[women laugh]
Oh, my little clown.
Old carrot top.
The best photos.
Ohh. Ohh.
We should be getting you Home, mother.
Hold on a minute. Here's us at mount rushmore.
Do you remember, truman, When dad was still with us?
That was quite a drive. You slept The whole way there.
Truman: It looks so small.
Things always do When you look back, darling.
Oh, look, truman. The happiest day Of our lives.
Oh, look. Jean, jodie, joanne.
Doesn't she look Beautiful, truman?
Well, she still does.
And there's lots of pages Left over for baby photos.
I would like to hold A grandchild in my arms Before i go.
Angela, we really should Be getting you home. I'll take her.
No, no, no. You stay, relax.
Enjoy yourself. Your favorite show Will be coming on.
Besides, we have Something to discuss.
A certain person's Birthday.
Oh, i see.
Tv announcer: and there'll be Another episode Of  i love lucy Same time tomorrow.
But right now it's time For   golden oldies.
Tonight, we present The enduring, much-loved classic
Show me the way to go home.
A hymn of praise To small-town life,
Where we learn that you don't Have to leave home
To discover What the world's all about, And that no one is poor Who has friends.
Full of laughter and love, Pain and sadness,
But ultimately redemption,
We share the trials And tribulations Of the abbott family.
Note the touching performance of Ronald brierly as uncle buddy.
And that scene with the bowl Of cherries is gonna have you Splitting your sides With laughter all over again.
And there'll be tears, too, when david and jennifer Are reunited.
But enough from me.
Let's join the abbotts In camden village.
[birds chirping]
[radio static]
Oh. Thank you, sweetie.
I need to talk to you, But let's go outside.
Oh, sweetie, i'd love to, But i'm really late.
What's your rush?
Surgery.
There was that elevator Disaster downtown. It was on the news Last night.
This cable just snapped.
This elevator, It just plummeted down 10 flights.
The non-union workers.
Just monsters. You know, that building, It's right next door To where you work.
Can you imagine if you Had been in there?
It's not even worth Thinking about.
Anyway, I have an amputation On one of the young Women in that elevator.
She's very young. It's very sad.
Anyway, wish me luck.
I'll cross my fingers For you.
[brakes squeal]
Uh, excuse me. Hi. Excuse me. May i help you?
Oh, uh...Yes. I'm looking for my wife, Nurse burbank.
It's very important. I'm afraid that That's not possible. She's in pre-op.
Sure. Ok, fine. Can you pass along a message?
I'll try.
Can you tell her I had to go to fiji And that i'll call her When i get there?
When you-- When you get to fiji?
You got it.
Fine. I'll tell her.
Thank you so much.
Sorry. It's ok.
我帮你
He's here.
Meryl: i know, i know. Shh, shh, shh.
Scalpel.
Ahem.
I'm now making My primary incision
Just above the right knee.
[loud clang]
按着她
Nicely done.
This isn't Going to be pretty.
It's just Beautiful. Beautiful job.
I'll just let someone else Tidy up here.
(乘客留意)
(可能发生在你身上)
I'm sorry to keep you. Oh, that's ok.
How can i help?
I would like to book A flight to fiji.
When would you like To leave?
Today.
[beep]
I'm sorry. I don't have anything For at least a month.
A month?
It's the busy season.
You want to book the flight?
It doesn't matter. I'll make other Arrangements, ok?
Man: Last call for chicago!
All aboard!
[whistles]Thank you.
Windy city, here we come.
Hi. Hi.
Hello.
Hi.
Truman: sisters.
Hey, mom, isn't that--
Mom: shh. Face the front.
[gears grind]
[engine stalls]
[radiator hissing]Everybody off. We've got a problem.
I'm sorry, son.
His father was from Chicago, wasn't he?
No. His dentist Was from pensacola.
His father Was from des moines.
But how come he wants To go to chicago?
He's not going to chicago. He's not going anywhere.
He has to have it out With meryl.
[pluto barks]
Truman?
Honey, are you ok?
Get in.
Truman.
Look.
What? Shh.
I predict That in just a moment
We will see a lady On a red bike,
Followed by a man With flowers
And a volkswagen beetle With a dented fender.
Truman, please. Truman: look.
Lady...
Flowers...
Both: and...
Truman, this is silly.
There it is! There it is!
There's that dented Beetle! Yes!
Aaaaaah!
Ha ha ha!
Don't you want to know How i did that?
I'll tell you. They're on a loop.
They go around the block. They come back.
They go around again. They just go Round and round. Round and round.
I invited rita and marlon For a barbecue on sunday.
I won't be here Sunday.
And i need you to remind me That we need more charcoal.
Are you listening To a word i'm saying?
You're upset because You want to go to fiji. Is that it?
Ok, ok, go.
I think you should save For a few months And then go. There.
Are you happy now?
I want to go take a shower.
Let's go now.
I'm ready to go now. Why wait?
Early bird Gathers no moss. Rolling stone catches The worm, right?
[laughs]
Meryl: truman, What are you doing?
Oh!
Truman!
Where shall we go? Where shall we go?
Truman, where Are we going?
I don't really know. I guess i'm being spontaneous.
Somebody help me! I'm being spontaneous!
Meryl: truman. Forget fiji. Can't very well drive To fiji, can we?
No.
What about Atlantic city?
Oh, no, you hate To gamble.
That's right, I do, don't i? So why would you want To go there?
Because i never have.
That's why people Go places, isn't it?
Truman, truman, I think i'm gonna throw up.
Me, too.
Blocked at every turn.
Beautifully synchronized, Don't you agree?
You're blaming me For the traffic?
Should i?
Truman... Let's go home.
You're right. We could be stuck Here for hours.
It could be like this All the way to atlantic city. Let's go back.
I'm sorry. I don't know What got into me.
Meryl: can you Please slow down?
Yes, i can.
Truman! Truman! That's our turnoff! I changed my mind again.
What's new orleans like This time of year?
Mardi gras! Whoo! Ha ha ha!
[honking]
Whoo!
Look, meryl, same road, No cars.
It's magic. Ha ha ha!
You let me out. You're Not right in the head.
You want to destroy Yourself, do it on your own.
I think i'd like A little company.
Oh, truman... You knew This would happen.
You know you can't Drive over water.
Let's go home Where you'll feel safe.
Give me your hand. Sweetie--
Drive.
Truman!
We shouldn't be doing this! We're breaking the law!
Oh, my! You can do it!
Please, don't!
You can make it! Truman!
Aah! Oh, we're over! We're over the bridge! We're over the bridge!
We're over? We're over the bridge. We're over the bridge.
We're over!
Ha ha ha ha!
(山火警告：极度危险)
Truman! What About that sign? They're exaggerating. We'll be fine.
Exaggerating? Do you believe that?
[yelling]
Oh, my! Oh, my! Truman, we're on fire!
It's ok. We're on fire! It's ok. It's just smoke.
You ok? Yes.
Want to do it again? No! Ha ha ha ha!
Truman, stop! Oh, god!
Oh! So, what are we going To do for money When we get To new orleans?
I have my seahaven Bank card.
We're just going to eat Into our savings, is that it?
I'm going to have to call Your mother when we get there.
She's going To be worried sick.
I don't know how She's going to take this.
What now?
Loudspeaker: red alert! This is a red alert!
[people yelling]
[car horns honking]Truman, it looks like A leak at the plant.
Back up! Back up! Leak at the plant. We had to shut her down.
Is there Any way around?
Whole area's Being evacuated.
Is there Anything i can do? No, ma'am.
Thank you For your help. You're welcome, Truman.
Truman.
Truman! Truman!
Truman, come back!
Truman! Truman! Stop him!
Unh! Truman!
[whistles blowing]
Head to the left!
Aah! Aah!
Stay away!
Unh! Aah!
Unh! No!
No!
Radio: ...now in custody.
[truman groaning]
Thank you both so much For your help. I really appreciate it.
He's lucky to be Alive, ma'am. Next time, we'll have To file charges.
I understand.
Thanks again. Good night.
Let me get you Some help, truman.
You're not well.
Why do you want To have a baby with me?
You can't stand me.
That's not true.
[scoffs]
Why don't you let me fix you Some of this new mococoa drink?
All natural cocoa beans From the upper slopes Of mount nicaragua.
No artificial sweeteners.
What the hell Are you talking about?
Who are you talking to?
I've tasted other cocoas. This is the best.
What the hell does this Have to do with anything?
Tell me what's happening!
You're having a nervous Breakdown, that's what.
You're part of this, Aren't you?
Truman! Meryl!
You...are...scaring me!
No, you're scaring me, meryl.
What are you going to do?
Dice me? Slice me And peel me?
There are So many choices!
Aah! Do something!
What? What did you say?
Who are you talking to?
Nothing. I didn't Say anything. I didn't Say anything.
You said, "do something." No, i didn't. I wasn't Talking to anybody.
Talk to me! I don't know anything! Please stop!
[banging]Stay where You are!
Truman?
Oh, thank god! Oh, thank god!
[sobbing]
How can anyone Expect me To carry on under These conditions?
It's unprofessional!
Shh, it's ok.
Everything's Gonna be ok.
Oh, god!
It's all Gonna be fine.
I don't know what To think, marlon.
Maybe i'm losing My mind, but...
It feels like the whole world Revolves around me somehow.
That's a lot of world For one man, truman.
Sure that's not Wishful thinking?
You wishing you'd made Something more Out of yourself?
Come on, who hasn't Sat in the john,
Had an imaginary interview On  seahaven tonight?
Who hasn't wanted To be somebody?
This is different. Everybody seems to be in on it.
I've been your best friend Since we were 7 years old.
The only way you and i ever Made it through school was by cheating off Each other's test papers.
Jesus, they were identical.
But i always felt safe Knowing that.
'Cause whatever The answer was,
We were right together And we were wrong together.
Remember when i stayed up All night in your tent
'Cause you wanted To play north pole?
And i got pneumonia?
[laughing]You remember that?
You were out of school For about a month.
You're the closest thing I ever had to a brother.
I know that things...
Haven't really worked Out for either of us
Like we used to Dream they would.
I know that feeling, When it's like everything's Slipping away...
You don't want To believe it
So you look for answers Somewhere else, but...
Well...the point is...I'd gladly walk in front Of traffic for you.
Marlon: well...The point is, I would gladly Step in front of traffic For you, truman.
And the last thing I'd ever do is lie to you.
And the last thing That i would ever do...
Is lie to you.
I mean, think about it, Truman.
If everybody Is in on it...
I'd have to be In on it, too.
I'm not in on it, Truman, because...
There is no "it."
You were right about One thing, though.
What's that?
The thing that Started all this.
Yep. I found him For you, truman.
That's why I came by tonight.
I'm sure he's got Quite a story to tell.
Go to him.
Easy on the fog.
[keyboard clicking]Stand by, crane cam.
Crane cam.
Button cam 3.
I never stopped believing.
Christof: And wide, curb cam 8.
My son! Oh!
Move in For a closeup? No, no, no.
Move back and...
Fade up music.
[music swells]
And now go in close.
All those Years wasted.
I'll make it up To you, son.
I swear.
[music swells]
Dad.
Yes!
[laughing]
Bravo. That was a really great Experience.
Congratulations.
Ok, quiet down. Let's concentrate.
Chloe: That was good work.
Whoo!
Tech: let's get Some champagne up here.
Congratulations. Moses: brilliant, christof. Just brilliant.
Roman: It just broke my heart.
Well done, everyone!
Bravo!
(楚门喝尼加拉瓜山出产)
(由顶级可可炼制的莫可可)
Announcer: 1.7 billion Were there for his birth.
(巨星诞生)
220 countries tuned in For his first step.
The world stood still For that stolen kiss,
And as he grew, So did the technology.
An entire human life Recorded on an intricate Network of hidden cameras
And broadcast live and Unedited 24 hours a day,
7 days a week to an audience Around the globe.
Coming to you now From seahaven island, Enclosed in the largest Studio ever constructed
And along with The great wall of china,
One of only 2 manmade structures Visible from space,
"真人表演"已经踏入
Now in its 30th great year, It's...
What a week it's been.
I don't know about you--I was on pins and needles The entire time.
Hello and good evening. I'm your host mike michaelson,
And welcome to  tru-talk, Our forum for issues Growing out of the show.
But tonight, Something very special indeed,
A rare and Exclusive interview With the show's Conceiver and creator.
So, come with us now as we Go live to the lunar room On the 221st floor Of the omni cam echosphere
Where we'll find the world's Greatest tele-visionary--
The designer and architect Of the world within a world
That is seahaven island-- Christof.
Before we begin, I'd like to thank you On behalf of our audience For granting this interview.
We know how demanding Your schedule is And we all know how jealously You guard your privacy.
This, sir, Is indeed an honor.
Don't mention it.
Well, the catalyst for The recent dramatic events
On the show has been Truman's father, kirk
And his attempts To infiltrate the show.
But before we get into that, I think it's worth noting
That this is not the first time Someone from the outside
Has attempted To reach truman, is it? Christof: we have had Close calls in the past.
Man: truman! It's television!
Yes! Yes! I did it! I'm on  the truman show!
Mike: but there's never Been anything to compare
With this most recent Breach in security--
The first intruder to be A former cast member.
A dead one at that.
Gotta say, writing kirk Back in--masterstroke.
Since kirk started this Crisis in truman's life,
I came to the conclusion That only he could end it.
Truman! Truman!
No! That's off limits! Why? What's Over there?
[construction noises]
Nothing. It's dangerous. That's all.
You've got to know Your limitations, truman.
Mike: but let's remind Viewers exactly why Dad was written out In the first place.
Christof: as truman grew up, We were forced To manufacture ways To keep him on the island.
I'd like to be An explorer, Like the great Magellan.
You're too late. There's really Nothing left to explore.
[snarling]
Christof: finally, i came up With kirk's drowning.
Mike: most effective. Truman's been terrified Of the water ever since.
Christof: when kirk read The synopsis of the episode,
He was disappointed To say the least.
Jesus! I'm sure that's what caused Him to break onto the set.
But how do you intend to Explain his 22-year absence?
Amnesia.
Brilliant.
Let's take Some viewer phone calls.
Charlotte, north carolina, You're on with christof.
Man: uh, yeah, Hi, christof.
I was wondering how many Cameras you got in that town.
Somewhere in The vicinity of 5,000.
Man: that's A lot of cameras.
Remember, we started With just one.
He was curious From birth. Premature by 2 weeks.
Almost as if he couldn't Wait to get started.
Mike: his eagerness To leave his mother's womb
Was the very reason He was the one selected.
In competition with 5 other Unwanted pregnancies,
The casting of a show, Determined by an air date
Truman was the one Who arrived on cue.
Mike: incidentally, i believe Truman is the first child
To have been legally adopted By a corporation.
That's correct.
The show has generated Enormous revenues now,
Equivalent to the gross national Product of a small country.
People forget it takes The population
Of an entire country to Keep the show running.
Since the show is on 24-hours a day Without commercial interruption, All those staggering revenues Are generated By product placement.
That's true. Everything On the show is for sale.
From the actor's wardrobe, Food products, To the very homes They live in.
Mike: and all of it available In the truman catalog.
Operators are standing by.
Christof, let me ask you,
Why do you think truman Has never come close
To discovering the true nature Of his world until now?
We accept the reality Of the world With which we are Presented.
It's as simple as that.
The hague for christof. Hello? The hague?
All right, We've lost that call. Let's go to hollywood. You're on  tru-talk.
Hi, christof. I'd just Like to say one thing. You're a liar And a manipulator,
And what you've done To truman is sick!
Well, we remember This voice, don't we? How could we forget?
Mike: let's go To another call.
No, no, no. It's fine, mike.
I love to reminisce with Former members of the cast.
Sylvia...
As you announced so Melodramatically to the world,
You think because you batted Your eyes at truman once...
Flirted with him...Stole a few minutes Of air time with him...
To thrust yourself and your Politics into the limelight...
That you know him?
That you know What's right for him?
You really think you're In a position to judge him?
What right do you have To take a baby
And turn his life into Some kind of mockery?
Don't you ever Feel guilty?
I have given truman a chance To lead a normal life.
The world...The place you live in...Is the sick place.
Seahaven's the way The world should be.
He's not a performer. He's a prisoner.
Look at him! Look at What you've done to him!
He can leave at any time.
If his was more Than just a vague ambition,
If he was absolutely determined To discover the truth,
There's no way We could prevent him.
I think what distresses You really, caller,
Is that ultimately...Truman prefers his cell, As you call it.
That's where You're wrong.
You're so wrong, and He'll prove you wrong.
Mike: well, aside from The heated comments Of a very Vocal minority
It's been an overwhelmingly Positive experience.
Yes. For truman and For the viewing public.
Well, christof, I can't thank you enough
For giving so generously Of your time tonight.
I think it's safe to say now That this crisis is behind us
And truman is back To his old self,
We can look forward to some Exciting new developments?
Well, mike, the big news
Is that meryl Will be leaving truman In an upcoming episode
And a new romantic interest Will be introduced.
Mike: aha. I'm determined television's First on-air conception
Will still take place.
Well, another television Milestone straight ahead.
You heard it here first.
It has been a singular honor And pleasure, sir.
Christof...thank you. Thank you, mike.
[birds chirping]
Hey, simeon. What?
Is he looking at us?
Jesus, do you Think he knows?
Hello?
Better call Christof.
Hello? Come in, major burbank.
[whistling]
Ha ha! [snorts]
He's back To his old self. Thank god.
[laughing]
That's an unusual Cat, my man.
I hereby...Proclaim this planet...
Trumania Of the burbank galaxy.
Is he going? Hallway camera.
That one's for free.
Keep up with him. He'll move fast.
Stand by, All house cameras.
Morning!
All: morning. In case i don't see you...
All: good afternoon, Good evening, And good night.
Good afternoon...Good morning.
...evening, And good night.
Morning. Morning, spencer.
How's it going? Hmm, let me check.
Vital signs are good.
[barking]Whoa, pluto! Whoop!
Both: Good morning, truman! Oh, look who's here.
Beautiful day, Isn't it? Every single day.
The policy-- We've thought about it...Both: and we're Gonna take it.
You're kidding? Both: no!
Great! Why don't we go up To my office right now, And we'll sign the papers?
Uh, next week Would be much better. Next week would be better.
All right. See you guys. Ok, bye now. See you next week.
Give me something To look forward to. You got it.
See, this isn't About insurance.
This is about The great variable--
When will death occur?
Could be a week, A month, a year.
Could be today.
Sunbather, Minding his own business,
Stabbed in the heart by the tip Of a runaway beach umbrella.
No way to guard against That kind of thing.
[truman laughs]
Uh, sorry, excuse me.
Uh, truman, this is vivien. Vivien, this is truman.
The two of you Are gonna be neighbors.
Oh.
I guess what i'm--
What i'm saying is that, Uh, life is...fragile.
Lawrence: Vivien, your office. Sorry.
What's that? Oh, i'm sorry. Uh...
You do? Oh, great.
Uh, let me Take your information.
[lawn mower buzzing]
Ready 2. Go to 2.
And back to medium.
And wide.
Psst!
I was just trying To train the kid to...
Never mind.
Christof: what's he doing In the basement?
He moved down there after Meryl packed up and left.
Why wasn't i told? Any unpredictable behavior Has to be reported.
Uh, he--he's just sleeping, I thought.
This the best shot We've got?
What's to see? What's on the clock cam?
It's an obstruction-- Obstruction.
What happened down there?
He was just tidying up His garbage. I was gonna call you
But halfway through He gave up, And he fell asleep.
I wanna check on The setups for the...Both: insurance Convention tomorrow.
Yes. Yeah.
Nice move.
[taps keyboard]
[beep]There you go.
Isolate the audio. Give me a closeup On his torso.
[beep]
[snoring]He's still breathing.
[sighs]
Where's chloe? Yes, sir. Call him.
What do you Want me to say? Tell him It's a wrong number.
[chloe dials phone]
[telephone rings]What took you so long?
Just had to wait for it.
[ring]They were busy. Here.
What's going on? I don't know. They're...
[ring]He came down into the room. He did nothing But stand around for a while.
Christof: Shut up and watch it!
Then we went To nightvision.
[ring]He's asleep.
[simeon scoffs]Christof: there! Stop it! What?
Zoom in. On which?
Under the chair there.
Simeon: uh-huh.
Christof: enhance it.
Simeon: is it--oh. Chloe: oh, my god.
I...if--he couldn't have Gone up the stairs. I definitely--he must Still be in the room.
Get marlon Over there. Right away.
[tires screech]
Marlon: truman! Surprise party!
Oh. Come on, buddy. I got a 6-pack of cold brewskis With our name on them.
Come on, pal. Come on, buddy.
[squeak]
[snoring]
Shit.
Marlon, find him. He's still in the room.
Come out, come out Wherever you are.
That's good. Keep it light.
I know you're in here. I'm gonna find ya.
Check under the table.
The closet, behind you.
Huh.
Gee. I wonder where he Could possibly be.
The lawn cam, Get me the lawn cam.
Don't look in the camera. Say something. Keep it going. Keep it going.
He's gone.
Cut transmission! Cut transmission?
Cut it!
[beep]Man: jesus! God in heaven!
[audience gasps]
Woman: Everything's black. Give me the phone.
[classical music playing]
(技术故障  请稍候)
[speaking Various languages]
I don't know where he is, But he's gone.
[clears throat]We've got every available Extra looking for him.
Uh, the principals Are helping out.
The crew, too, So every sector's covered.
What about prop cars? Yes, they've been Accounted for.
He has to be on foot.
He has the world's Most recognizable face. He can't disappear.
[siren]
[pluto barking, snarling]
Spencer: go. Hunt him. Hunt him. Yeah. Go find him, pluto. Good dog! Good dog!
All this fuss.
If he could just Hear my voice.
Truman! Truman!
Let me try.
Truman! It's me! Dad! Let's talk!
Yeah, i know.
Just about done With the square.
Got to go back to barrymore, Check the interiors. He's got to be in there.
Simeon: Barrymore, huh?
Uh-huh. But what about the college? Who's watching that? I don't know.
Send somebody Over there, ok? All right.
Take another man and get Down there now, all right?
I don't give a damn. Just Find the son of a bitch.
Get some batteries. This guy's Not gonna glow in the dark. Just get 'em down here.
I don't know what's going On. Reroute it back to me.
We need more light. We'll never find him This way.
What time is it?
It's way too early For that.
Cue the sun.
[people gasp]
Jeez! What time is it?
Christof, What's going on?
Did you know that there's A rumor circulating That he's dead?
You hear me? The media is having A feeding frenzy over this.
All the phone lines Are jammed,
And every network has A pirated shot of marlon Making an ass of himself In front of the camera.
The sponsors are threatening To rip up their contracts.
Why? We're getting higher Ratings with this graphic Than we've ever had On this show.
No sign of him.
Why don't you head back To town and join the others?
Everyone else is At first positions, ok?
Thank you.
Everyone's at first Positions, right?
Simeon: We've got the light. So he's got to Be there somewhere.
We're not Watching the sea.
Simeon: hang on a minute. Why would we watch the sea?
Sweep the harbor.
Bring up the harbor cameras. Shift all harbor cameras To computer, please.
Some of those are out, Aren't they?
Operator: yeah. We have 4 of them down, But we have The lighthouse cameras up.
All buoy cams, please. Moses: What's happening?
Operator: ok. Long lens, Short base cameras. Moses: why are we Looking at the water?
Operator: pan it, Will you, please?
Truman...
Where are you going?
How can he sail? He's in insurance.
Operator: isn't he Terrified of the water?
Resume transmission.
Resuming transmission.
I got 2 to 1 He doesn't make it. Man: hey, i want A piece of that. 2 to 1 He doesn't make it.
[key tapping]
Just leave 'em In the car.
Shh.
Let's get off This mast shot. We can't see his face.
Go to the cabin cam. Cabin cam.
There. Perfect.
That's our hero shot.
Let's get another boat Out there.
Ok. Listen, gus, i need you to Talk to the guys on the ferry.
Come on. Get it moving. Get it out of here.
[grinding]Gus: come on.
I'm just a bus driver.
Bottom line is, They can't drive the boat.
They're actors.
How do we stop him?
Ok, uh...
We're going to be accessing The weather program now.
So hold on to your hats.
You got that?
No. I think we're gonna Want to localize the storm Over the boat.
You can get The coordinates for that.
There's no rescue boat. He won't know what to do.
He'll turn back. He'll be too afraid.
[whispering]
There she blows.
(起动掣)
[motor stalling]Come on.
Give me some lightning.
[thunder]Again!
Hit him again!
For god's sake, christof, The whole world is watching.
We can't let him die In front of a live audience.
He was born in front Of a live audience.
[cheering]
Truman!
You can do it! Hold on!
Is that the best You can do?
You're gonna have To kill me!
On behalf of the studio, I demand that you Cease transmission. Keep running.
What shall we do With a drunken sailor early in the mornin'?
Increase the wind. Increase the wind!
[truman Continues singing]
I'm telling you For the last time.
How close is he? Very.
Capsize him. Tip him over. Damn you, Christof!
You can't. He's tied Himself to the boat! Shut up!
He's gonna drown, And he doesn't even care.
Do it. No. Do it!
[thunder]
That's enough.
[gagging]
[crash]
Oh.
Christof: I want to talk to him.
(出口)
Truman.
[gasps]You can speak.
[over speaker] I can hear you.
Who are you?
I am the creator Of a television show
That gives hope and joy And inspiration to millions.
Then who am i?
You're the star.
Was nothing real?
You were real.
That's what made you So good to watch.
Listen to me, truman.
There's no more truth Out there...
Than there is in the world I created for you.
The same lies.
The same deceit.
But in my world...
You have nothing To fear.
I know you better Than you know yourself.
You never had A camera in my head.
You're afraid.
That's why You can't leave.
It's ok, truman. I understand.
I have been watching you Your whole life.
I was watching When you were born.
I was watching when you Took your first step.
I watched you on your First day of school.
[laughs]The episode when you Lost your first tooth.
You can't leave, truman.
Please, god.
Christof: You belong here...
You can do it.
With me.
Talk to me.
Say something.
Well, say something, Goddamn it. You're on television.
You're live To the whole world.
In case i don't see you...
Good afternoon, good evening, And good night.
Yep.
Yeah! Yeah!
He did it. He did it.
He did it! He did it!
He made it! Yeah! All right, truman!
Cease transmission.
Ceasing Transmission.
[taps keyboard]
You want another slice? No. I'm ok.
What else is on? Let's see what else is on. Where's the tv guide?